Register of the John Davenport Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1941-1986., See also MONT PELERIN SOCIETY FILE/Speeches and writings by J. Davenport
  - Speech, English Speaking Union, n.d. (Folder 17: 10)
  - "The Stakes in Algeria," n.d. (Folder 17: 11)
  - "Union Political Spending vs. the Constitution," n.d. (Folder 17: 12)
  - "Unions, Employment, and Public Order," n.d. (Folder 17: 13)
  - "Unions vs. Government," n.d. (Folder 17: 14)
  - "U.C.L.A.: Social Security and Capital Formation," n.d. (Folder 17: 15)
  - "U.S. and the UN and the Byrd Amendment," n.d. (Folder 17: 16)
  - "The U.S. and World Economy," n.d. (Folder 17: 17)
    Notes and typescript
  - "The U.S. Economy: Achievement and Challenge," (Folder 17: 18)
  - "What Next Rhodesia?" n.d. (Folder 17: 19)
  - "Why Economics?" n.d. (Folder 17: 20)
  - "Why Not the KGB?" n.d. (Folder 17: 21)
  - "Will Ian Smith's Bold Gamble Succeed?" n.d. (Folder 17: 22)
  - "The Rising Tide of Wages," 1941 April. (Folder 17: 23)
  - "Towards an Economic Policy," 1942 February. (Folder 17: 24)
  - "Towards a Position," 1942 February 4. (Folder 17: 25)
  - "More Notes on 'Towards a Position'," 1942 February 9. (Folder 17: 26)
  - "Outer Mongolia," 1943 January. (Folder 17: 27)
  - "Future of American Russian Trade," 1943 December. (Folder 17: 28)
    Research notes and typescript
  - "Outer Mongolia and Manchuria," 1944 January. (Folder 17: 29)
  - "Russian Far East," 1944 March. (Folder 17: 30)
  - "France: The American Stakes," 1944 April. (Folder 17: 31)
  - "Statement and Prospectus for an American Magazine of Political Economy: 1944 April. (Folder 17: 32)
  - "Reconversion to What?" 1944 August. (Folder 17: 33)
  - "Report on Britain," 1944 September. (Folder 17: 34)
  - "The Job Before Us," 1945 January. (Folder 17: 35)
  - "The Sickness of Liberal Society," 1945 July. (Box-folder 18: 1)
  - "Whither Trade Unionism," 1946 August 27. (Folder 18: 2)
  - "The Testament of Henry Simons," The University of Chicago Law Review, 1946 December. (Folder 18: 3)
    Reprint
  - "The American Position," 1947-1948. (Folder 18: 4)
    Typescripts (three versions)
  - "The Failure of Economic Planning and Its Meaning for American Democracy," 1947 September. (Folder 18: 5)
  - "What Price Reduction?" 1947 September. (Folder 18: 6)
  - "Antitrust," 1948 June. (Folder 18: 7)
  - "Socialism by Default," 1949 March. (Folder 18: 8)
  - "Storm Warnings," 1949 April. (Folder 18: 9)
  - "A Note on Wage Policy," 1949 August. (Folder 18: 10)
  - "A Note on Productivity and the Balance of Payments," 1949 September. (Folder 18: 11)
  - "Power and Principle," 1949 November. (Folder 18: 12)
  - "Promise and Promises," 1957. (Folder 18: 13)
  - "As Her Wheel Rolls: A Note on Fortune," 1957 January 9. (Folder 18: 14)
  - "The New Japan," 1957 May 20. (Folder 18: 15)
  - "Germany: The Second Miracle," 1957 October. (Folder 18: 16)
  - "Arms and the Welfare State," The Yale Review, 1958 Spring. (Folder 18: 17)
  - "Some Points on Economic Development," 1958 April. (Folder 18: 18)
  - "The Rockefeller Report: A Dissent," 1958 May. (Folder 18: 19)
  - "The World's Greatest Need," 1959. (Folder 18: 20)
  - Speech, Boston, 1960. (Folder 18: 21)
  - "An Unrepentant Old Whig," Fortune, 1960 March. (Folder 18: 22)
  - Speech, Lexington Democratic Club, 1960 April 30. (Folder 18: 23)
  - "Towards Fuller Employment," 1960 July. (Folder 18: 24)
  - "The Economic Choice Ahead," speech, Radio Station WBAI, New York, 1960 November 2. (Folder 18: 25)
  - Speech, United States Chamber of Commerce, Washington, D.C., 1960 December 2. (Folder 18: 26)
  - "Toward the Profitable Wage," Fortune, 1961. (Folder 18: 27)
  - "In the Midst of Plenty," Fortune, 1961 March. (Folder 18: 28)
  - "Substantive Points on Gold," 1961 May 17. (Folder 18: 29)
    Notes, typescript, and correspondence
  - "The Burden of Proof," 1961 June. (Folder 18: 30)
  - "Right Across the Board," 66th NAM (National Association of Manufacturers) Congress of American Industry, New York City, 1961 December 6. (Box-folder 19: 1)
    Printed copy. Proceedings include paper by Friedrich A. von Hayek, "The Moral Element in Free Enterprise"
  - "What Do We Mean: Free Trade?" address to the 66th Congress of American Industry, New York City, 1961 December 6. (Folder 19: 2)
  - "Reflections for a Primer," 1962 June. (Folder 19: 3)
  - "The Priority of Politics Over Economics," Fortune, October 1962. (Folder 19: 4)
  - "Infamy in the Congo," 1963 January. (Folder 19: 5)
  - "An Ugly Face in Africa," Fortune, 1963 February. (Folder 19: 6)
  - "Economics and Human Values," 1963 Winter. (Folder 19: 7)
    Typescript and printed copy
  - The U.S. Economy, 1964. (Folder 19: 8)
    Reviews. Includes partial reprint, "Of the American Mission"
  - "The Free vs. the Manipulated Society," speech, Economic Club of New York, 1964 November 9. (Folder 19: 9)
  - "American Business and the New Economics," speech, Executives Club of Chicago, 1965 April 9. (Folder 19: 10)
  - "Right to Work," 1965 May. (Folder 19: 11)
  - Statement to the United States Senate Sub-Committee on Labor regarding Section 14(b) of the Taft-Hartley Act, 1965 June 25. (Folder 19: 12)
  - "The American Dollar," speech, Commonwealth Club of California, 1965 July 23. (Folder 19: 13)
  - Speech, New York Chamber of Commerce, 1965 November 4. (Folder 19: 14)
  - "Note on Rhodesia," 1966 January. (Folder 19: 15)
  - "The Case for Lifting Sanctions Against Rhodesia," 1966 April 20. (Folder 19: 16)
  - Letter to editor, New York Times, 1966 October 26. (Folder 19: 17)
    Clipping
  - "The Only Real Industrial Complex South of Milan," Fortune, 1966 December. (Folder 19: 18)
  - "The American Interest in Southern Africa," 1967 February. (Folder 19: 19)
  - "Hamlet Without the Ghost," 1967 February. (Folder 19: 20)
  - "Song in Time of Trouble," 1968 January. (Folder 19: 21)
    Typescript and printed copies
  - "America Is Not a Plan, or Even a Purpose," The National Observer, 1968 January 8. (Folder 19: 22)
  - "The Dollar, Gold and the Devil," speech, Economic Club of Detroit," 1968 February 19. (Folder 19: 23)
  - "The End of the Liberal Road," speech, Executives Club of Chicago, 1968 September 20. (Folder 19: 24)
  - "Into Hostile Country," Fortune, 1969 April. (Folder 19: 25)
  - "The Real Threat to the Nixon Economics," speech, Rotary Club of New York, 1969 August 28. (Folder 19: 26)
  - "Go Not in Search of Monsters," Human Events, 1968 August 31. (Folder 19: 27)
  - "Frank Ford Russell, 1904-1969," 1969 March. (Folder 19: 28)
  - "U.S. Policy Towards Southern Africa," 1969 March. (Folder 19: 29)
  - "The Chemical Industry Pushes," Fortune, 1969 April. (Folder 19: 30)
  - "The Costs of Remaining an Establishment," 1969 October 25. (Folder 19: 31)
  - "But Who Guides the Guide-Posts?" 1970. (Box-folder 20: 1)
  - "The Supreme Court in the Seventies," speech, 1970. (Folder 20: 2)
  - "Industry Starts the Big Clean-Up," Fortune, 1970 February. (Folder 20: 3)
  - Speech at Annual Municipal Forum of the Connecticut Bank and Trust Company, 1970 April 15. (Folder 20: 4)
  - "The Pied Pipers," 1970 May 18. (Folder 20: 5)
  - Interviews, 1970 May-June.
    - Professor Black, Yale Law School, May 21 (Folder 20: 6)
    - Professor Herbert Wechsler, Columbia Law School, May 26 (Folder 20: 7)
    - Judge Alfred Friendly, New York Circuit Court of Appeals, June 1 (Folder 20: 8)
    - Chief Justice Burger, June 16 (Folder 20: 9)
    - Associate Justice Potter Stewart, June 16 (Folder 20: 10)
  - "The United States, the Law and Chief Justice Burger," Fortune, 1970 September. (Folder 20: 11)
  - "The Long Pilgrimage," The Intercollegiate Review, no. 3, Winter 1970-1971. (Folder 20: 12)
  - "The Supreme Court in the Seventies: A Layman's View," The Record of the Association of the Bar of the City of New York, 1971 February. (Folder 20: 14)
  - "Labor's Legal Sanctuary," 1971 March. (Folder 20: 15)
  - Interview with Sidney Dean, 1971 July 13. (Folder 20: 16)
    Typescript with notes
  - "New Economic Policy," New York Times, 1971 August 22 (Folder 20: 17)
  - "Congress Must Curb Labor Union Monopoly," Human Events, 1971 September 11. (Folder 20: 18)
  - "The Road From Serfdom," Barron's, 1971 December 6. (Folder 20: 18)
  - "Pig in a Poke," Barron's, 1973 January 1. (Folder 20: 19)
  - Review of Emerson Schmidt, Union Power and the Public Interest, Barron's, 1973 May 7. (Folder 20: 20)
  - "Free Enterprise's Forgotten Virtues," 1973 July 27. (Folder 20: 21)
  - "Television vs. Press Freedom," 1974. (Folder 20: 22)
  - "A Heretical View of Labor Unions," Fortune, 1974 February. (Folder 20: 23)
  - "The Profit and Loss Economy," Monsanto Magazine, Spring 1974. (Folder 20: 24)
  - "Labor Union Power: The Bigger Coverup," National Republic, 1974 August 2. (Folder 20: 25)
  - Remarks at the ISI Conference, Malibu Beach, California, 1974 August 22. (Folder 20: 26)
  - "Beaches of the Mind," Fortune, 1974 November. (Folder 20: 27)
    Correspondence, printed copy, and reprint
  - "Needed: A Turnaround in Ideas," Wall Street Journal, 1975 April 22. (Folder 20: 28)
  - "The Market and Human Values," speech at Ludwig von Mises Lecture Series, Hillsdale College, Hillsdale, Michigan, 1975 July. (Folder 20: 29)
  - "Classical Medicine for the Economy," Human Events, 1975 October 5. (Folder 20: 30)
  - "The Classical Medicine," The Freeman, vol. 26, no. 1, 1976 January. (Folder 20: 31)
  - Interviews, 1976 February-March.
    - February 3
      - William Merrill (Folder 20: 32)
      - Nicholas Norton (Folder 20: 33)
      - Stanley Thomas (Folder 20: 34)
      - John Young (Folder 20: 35)
    - February 4
      - David Edgehill (Folder 20: 36)
      - William Fisher (Folder 20: 37)
      - Mr. Hill and Mr. Little (Folder 20: 38)
      - Keith Weikel (Folder 20: 39)
    - March 3 - Phillip Fleming (Folder 20: 40)
    - March 10 - Milton Friedman (Folder 20: 41)
  - "U.S. Should Pressure Cuba on Angola," Human Events, 1976 March 13. (Box-folder 21: 1)
  - "A Question of Limits," 1976 April. (Folder 21: 2)
  - "U.S. Rhodesian Policy," Wall Street Journal, 1976 April 21. (Folder 21: 3)
  - "Civilization at Risk," Modern Age, 1976 Summer. (Folder 21: 4)
  - "The Welfare State vs. the Public Welfare," Fortune, 1976 June. (Folder 21: 5)
    Holograph and printed copy
  - "A Heartening Message From Youth," The Freeman, 1976 October. (Folder 21: 6)
  - "The Moral Environment," paper, Committee for Monetary Research and Education meeting, Boulder, Colorado, 1976 November. (Folder 21: 7)
    Typescript and various materials from the meeting
  - "The Promise of Southwest Africa," 1976 December. (Folder 21: 8)
  - Critique of Channel 13's presentation of July 15 entitled "Portrait of a Terrorist," featuring Robert Mugabe, 1977. (Folder 21: 9)
    Typescript and correspondence
  - "Re: Rhodesian Information Service," 1977 March. (Folder 21: 10)
  - "Embargo on Chrome," Barron's, 1977 March 21. (Folder 21: 11)
  - "Letter to a Friend," 1977 May 18. (Folder 21: 12)
  - "Rhodesian Blackout," National Review, 1977 April 15. (Folder 21: 13)
  - "Is Rhodesian Problem Plot or Folly?" Human Events, 1977 October 8. (Folder 21: 14)
  - "The Mixed Up Economy," 1977 November. (Folder 21: 15)
  - Lecture, Georgetown University, Washington, D.C., 1978. (Folder 21: 16)
    Handwritten and typewritten drafts and notes
  - "Does It Matter Who's Head of the Fed?" Fortune, 1978 January 30. (Folder 21: 17)
  - "Ian Smith: An American-Rhodesian Perspective," National Review, 1978 April 14. (Folder 21: 18)
  - "Management in an Over-Managed Society," 1978 June. (Folder 21: 19)
  - "Lift Rhodesian Sanctions Now!" 1978 June 26. (Folder 21: 20)
  - "Voting for Capitalism," Fortune, 1978 July 17. (Folder 21: 21)
  - "The U.S. Rediscovers the Economics of Supply," Fortune, 1978 October 23. (Folder 21: 22)
  - "Unions, Employment, and Public Order," 1978 December. (Folder 21: 23)
  - "Inflation," 1979. (Folder 21: 24)
    Handwritten notes
  - "Southern Africa: The Fateful Struggle," 1979. (Folder 21: 25)
  - "Unions, Employment and Public Order in the United States," 1979. (Folder 21: 26)
  - "Banking and Inflation: The Need for Real Capital Formation," 1979 March. (Folder 21: 27)
  - "Unions, Unemployment and Public Order," Journal of Social and Political Studies, 1979 Summer. (Folder 21: 28)
  - "Stop Picking on Rhodesia," Washington Star, 1979 June 5. (Folder 21: 29)
  - "Economics and Human Values," 1979 July. (Box-folder 22: 1)
  - "The Challenge to Management," speech, American Management Associates, 1979 July 17. (Folder 22: 2)
  - "The New Politics of Private Enterprise," speech, 1979 December 7. (Folder 22: 3)
    Handwritten and typewritten drafts and typescript
  - "Poets and Economists," Writing for Fortune, Time Inc., New York, 1980. (Folder 22: 4)
  - "Much I Have Traveled in the Realms of Gold," lecture, Conference of the Committee for Monetary Research and Education, 1980 March 23. (Folder 22: 5)
  - "The New Allure of the Gold Standard," Fortune, 1980 April 7. (Folder 22: 6)
  - "A Testing Time for Monetarism," Fortune, 1980 October 6. (Folder 22: 7)
  - "General Notes: Washington," 1981 February. (Folder 22: 8)
  - "Christianity, the Market and Beyond," Imprimis, 1981 March. (Folder 22: 9)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, 1981 August. (Folder 22: 10)
  - "Challenge and Opportunity," speech, Rutgers Community Mental Health Center, 1981 August 3. (Folder 22: 11)
  - "Time for Reagan Doctrine on Labor," New York Times, 1981 August 18. (Folder 22: 12)
  - "Measuring the Pain in Reagan's Cuts," Fortune, 1981 November 2. (Folder 22: 13)
    Typewritten draft and printed copy
  - "Reflections on the 'The Desk'," 1982 June. (Folder 22: 14)
  - "A New Target for Supply-Siders: Cost Containment," Human Events, 1982 December 25. (Folder 22: 15)
  - "Bretton Woods: A Journalist's Impression," A Monetary Agenda for World Growth, Quantum, Boston, 1983. (Folder 22: 16)
  - "Why Not Make Employment Profitable?" 1983 January. (Folder 22: 17)
  - "What We Can Learn From Bretton Woods," Human Events, 1983 June 25. (Folder 22: 18)
  - "The Lessons of Bretton Woods," paper, Pre-Williamsburg International Monetary Conference, Washington, D.C., 1983 May 17. (Folder 22: 19)
  - "Why Not Deregulate Labor?" The Freeman, 1983 October. (Folder 22: 20)
  - "Baruch Speaking," Fortune, 1984 February 20. (Folder 22: 21)
  - "Beyond the Market," 1984 September. (Folder 22: 22)
  - Letter to the editor, Wall Street Journal, 1984 November 5. (Folder 22: 23)
  - "Heel or No Heel," 1985. (Folder 22: 24)
  - "Beyond the Market," The Freeman, 1985 January. (Folder 22: 25)
  - Review of George Stigler, The Intellectual and the Marketplace(1984) and other writings, 1985 January. (Folder 22: 25)
    Notes, typescripts and correspondence
  - "The Anti-Apartheid Threat," The Freeman, 1985 August. (Folder 22: 26)
  - "Prefatory Note," 1985 August 10. (Box-folder 23: 1)
  - "A Time for Veto," 1986 September 3. (Folder 23: 2)
- MONT PELERIN SOCIETY FILE, 1947-1986
  - General
    - General (Folder 23: 3-5)
    - Membership, 1981 (Folder 23: 6)
  - Correspondence with Ralph Harris, 1968 (Folder 23: 7)
  - Meetings file
    - General (Folder 23: 8)
    - 1959 September (Folder 23: 9)
    - 1974 September (Folder 23: 10)
    - 1976 August (Folder 23: 11)
    - 1980 September (Folder 23: 12-13)
    - 1981 August/September (Folder 23: 14)
    - 1982 September (Folder 23: 15)
    - 1984 September (Folder 23: 16)
    - 1984 September (Box-folder 24: 1)
    - 1985 March (Folder 24: 2)
    - 1986 September (Folder 24: 3)
  - Newsletters, 1981-1986 (Folder 24: 4)
  - Speeches and writings by J. Davenport
    - General. (Folder 24: 5)
      Drafts and notes relating to the Mont Pèlerin Society
    - "History of the Mont Pèlerin Society, n.d. (Folder 24: 6)
    - "Pilgrimage of Bus Ride," remarks at Mont Pèlerin Society meeting, 1959 September. (Folder 24: 7)
    - "End of the Beginning," paper, Mont Pèlerin Society meeting, 1960 July 26. (Folder 24: 8)
    - "The Long Pilgrimage," paper, Mont Pèlerin Society meeting, 1970 September. (Folder 24: 9)
    - "Reflections on Mont Pèlerin," 1981 July. (Folder 24: 10)
- NATIONAL RIGHT TO WORK LEGAL DEFENSE FOUNDATION FILE, 1969-1987
  - General
    - General (Folder 24: 11-12)
    - Annual Reports
      - 1980 (Folder 24: 13)
      - 1982 (Folder 24: 14)
    - Balance sheet and financial statement, 1979-1980 (Folder 24: 15)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1973-1986 (Folder 24: 16)
      - Larson, Reed, 1986-1987 (Folder 24: 17)
    - History of the foundation, 1979 (Box-folder 25: 1)
    - News releases, 1971-1982 (Folder 25: 2)
    - Newsletters, 1976-1987 (Folder 25: 3)
  - Buckley, William F. - Lawsuit, 1971 (Folder 25: 4)
  - Court cases, 1969-1972 (Folder 25: 5)
  - Executive Committee (Folder 25: 6)
  - Farm labor (Folder 25: 7)
  - Legal Defense Program (Folder 25: 8-10)
  - Marker-Connally case (Box-folder 26: 1)
  - Meetings
    - General
      - 1984
        - May 5 (Folder 26: 2)
        - September 13 (Folder 26: 3)
        - November 27 (Folder 26: 4)
      - 1985
        - February 26 (Folder 26: 5)
        - May 11 (Folder 26: 6)
    - Board of Trustees, 1983 May 7 (Folder 26: 7)
  - Seminars (Folder 26: 8)
  - Task Force on Violence (Folder 26: 9)
  - Textbook evaluations (Folder 26: 10)
- NATIONAL RIGHT TO WORK COMMITTEE FILE, 1971-1987
  - General
    - General (Folder 26: 11-13)
    - General (Box-folder 27: 1-3)
    - Correspondence, 1982-1987 (Folder 27: 4)
    - News releases, 1986 (Folder 27: 5)
    - Newsletters, 1982-1987 (Folder 27: 6)
    - Printed matter
      - Right to Work, 1972-1987 (Folder 27: 7)
      - Violence Task Force Report, 1982 (Folder 27: 8)
  - Education (Folder 27: 9)
  - Executive Committee meeting, 1983 February 15 (Folder 27: 10)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1965-1987
  - Accuracy in Media, Inc. (Folder 27: 11)
  - American Conservative Union (Folder 27: 12)
  - American Economic Foundation (Folder 27: 13)
  - American Enterprise Institute (Box-folder 28: 1)
  - American-Rhodesian Association (Folder 28: 2)
  - The Americas Foundation (Folder 28: 3)
  - Angola (Folder 28: 4-6)
  - Anti-apartheid legislation in the United States, 1985-1986 (Folder 28: 7)
  - Apartheid - South Africa (Folder 28: 8)
  - Armstrong, Lucy (Folder 28: 9)
  - Barron's (Folder 28: 10)
  - Barron's Financial Weekly (Folder 28: 11)
  - Black nationalism - United States (Folder 28: 12)
  - Block grants - United States (Folder 28: 13)
  - Bryn Mawr Presbyterian Church (Folder 28: 14)
  - Budget - United States (Folder 28: 15)
  - Budget - United States (Box-folder 29: 1-6)
  - Budget - United States (Box-folder 30: 1-2)
  - Byrd Amendment, 1977 (Folder 30: 3)
  - Capital markets - United States (Folder 30: 4)
  - Chrome production - Rhodesia (Folder 30: 5)
  - Churchill, Winston (Folder 30: 6-8)
  - Civil rights - United States (Box-folder 31: 1)
  - Colonialism (Folder 31: 2)
  - Commission on Rhodesian Opinion (Folder 31: 3)
  - Committee for Monetary Research and Education (Folder 31: 4)
  - Commodity exchanges (Folder 31: 5)
  - Concerned Educators Against Forced Unionism
    - General (Folder 31: 6)
    - Seminars
      - 1980 (Folder 31: 7)
      - 1984 (Folder 31: 8)
  - Crime - United States (Folder 31: 9)
  - Davenport, Marcia (Folder 31: 10)
  - Debt - United States (Folder 31: 11)
  - Developing countries (Folder 31: 12)
  - Dirigism (Folder 31: 13)
  - Dure, Leon (Folder 31: 14)
  - Dworkin, Ronald (Folder 31: 15)
  - Economic Club of New York (Folder 31: 16)
  - Economic conditions - Rhodesia (Box-folder 32: 1-2)
  - Economic policy
    - Austria (Folder 32: 3)
    - United States (Folder 32: 4-8)
    - United States (Box-folder 33: 1-4)
  - Economic stabilization - United States (Folder 33: 5-6)
  - Education
    - Africa (Folder 33: 7)
    - Rhodesia (Folder 33: 8)
    - United States (Box-folder 34: 1-2)
  - Erhard, Ludwig (Folder 34: 3)
  - Fama, Eugene (Folder 34: 4)
  - Federal Reserve Bank
    - Minneapolis, 1977-1979 (Folder 34: 5)
    - New York, 1978-1980 (Folder 34: 6)
    - St. Louis
      - "International Economic Conditions"
        - 1980-1982 (Folder 34: 7)
        - 1983-1985 (Folder 34: 8)
        - 1985-1986 (Folder 34: 9)
      - "Monetary Trends"
        - 1980-1982 (Box-folder 35: 1)
        - 1982-1987 (Folder 35: 2)
      - "National Economic Trends," 1983 October (Folder 35: 3)
  - Federal Reserve System (U.S.) (Folder 35: 4-9)
  - Federal Reserve System (U.S.) (Box-folder 36: 1-4)
  - Finance, Public - United States (Folder 36: 5)
  - First National City Bank, New York
    - General (Folder 36: 6)
    - Monthly bank letters, 1961-1963 (Folder 36: 7)
  - Fisher, Antony (Folder 36: 8)
  - Foreign Policy Research Institute (Box-folder 37: 1)
  - Fortune magazine
    - Directive by J. Davenport for the editorial development of Fortune, n.d. (Folder 37: 2)
    - Remarks by J. Davenport on Fortune's changing of the guard, 1965 October 18. (Folder 37: 3)
  - Foundation of Law and Society (Folder 37: 4)
  - Free enterprise - United States (Folder 37: 5)
  - Friedman, Milton (Folder 37: 6)
  - Gold Commission (U.S.) (Folder 37: 7)
  - Gold standard
    - General (Folder 37: 8)
    - United States (Folder 37: 9)
  - Grant's Interest Rate Observer
    - 1983-1985 (Folder 37: 10)
    - 1985-1986 (Folder 37: 11)
    - 1986-1987 (Box-folder 38: 1)
  - Greyhound Bus Lines strike, 1983 November-December (Folder 38: 2)
  - Gross national product - United States (Folder 38: 3)
  - Haber, Irving (Folder 38: 4)
  - Hayek, Friedrich A. von (Folder 38: 5-6)
  - Haynsworth, Clement, Judge (Folder 38: 7)
  - Huntington Family Association (Folder 38: 8)
  - Imported strategic raw materials (Folder 38: 9)
  - Intercollegiate Studies Institute, Bryn Mawr, Pennsylvania
    - General (Folder 38: 10)
    - Seminar, 1973 August 6-10 (Folder 38: 11)
  - International Institute for Economic Research, Los Angeles, California (Folder 38: 12)
  - Katanga (Folder 38: 13)
  - Kemp, Jack (Folder 38: 14)
  - Labor and laboring classes - United States (Folder 38: 15-16)
  - Labor and laboring classes - United States (Folder 39: 1)
  - Labor unions - United States (Folder 39: 2-7)
  - Labor unions - United States. (Box-folder 40: 1-2)
    Includes typescript report by J. Davenport on union coercive power, n.d.
  - Lefferts, Halleck (Folder 40: 3)
  - Medicine - United States (Folder 40: 4-5)
  - Mental health services - United States (Folder 40: 6-10)
  - Mental health services - United States (Box-folder 41: 1-4)
  - Minimum wage - United States (Folder 41: 5)
  - Monetary policy
    - International (Folder 41: 6)
    - United States (Folder 41: 7-9)
    - United States (Box-folder 42: 1-7)
  - Morris, Robert (Box-folder 43: 1)
  - Namibia (Folder 43: 2-3)
  - National Committee to Restore Internal Security (Folder 43: 4)
  - National Federation of Independent Business (Folder 43: 5)
  - The New Economic Review, 1980 April-July (Folder 43: 6)
  - Nuclear energy (Folder 43: 7)
  - Okinawa (Ryukyu Islands) (Folder 43: 8)
  - Permanent South African Mission to the United Nations (Folder 43: 9)
  - Philadelphia Society (Folder 43: 10-11)
  - Portuguese in Africa (Folder 43: 12)
  - Psychology - United States (Box-folder 44: 1-2)
  - Public welfare - United States (Folder 44: 3-5)
  - Racial discrimination - Rhodesia (Folder 44: 6)
  - Rand, Ayn (Folder 44: 7)
  - Rhodesia
    - General (Folder 44: 8-10)
    - General (Box-folder 45: 1-5)
    - General (Box-folder 46: 1-6)
    - General (Box-folder 47: 1-3)
    - Clippings
      - 1976 April-November (Folder 47: 4)
      - 1977
        - January-February (Folder 47: 5)
        - June-December (Folder 47: 6)
    - Comments by Dean Acheson, 1966-1967 (Folder 47: 7)
    - Printed matter
      - Focus on Rhodesia, Volumes 1-4 (Folder 47: 8)
      - Rhodesian Viewpoint, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 48: 1)